ジェハ まだ町か
Jae-ha, you're going into town again?
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
ここ最近 何しに行ってんだよ
Why have you been going there so often lately?
I'm going to recruit someone.
今日はちょっと 勧誘
Shudder
なんか昨日から悪寒が
I've been feeling a chill since yesterday.
どうかしたの
Is something wrong?
いや
No...
otome yo
O maiden!
akatsuki ni moeagare
Flare up in the dawning sun!
muchi de kayowaku mamorareru dake no
I want to tear off the guise of the ignorant
hime nugisutete watashi wa ikitai
Frail protected princess and live
mukashi yori sukoshi dake suki ni nareta
To conquer the color of the burning dawn
akatsuki no sora no iro nabikase
That I've recently started enjoying
rinzen to tsuyoku
With strength and commanding presence
kedakaku sora wo miagete
I strive to be someone I'm proud of
hokoreru jibun ni narou
And looking up idealistically to the sky
mamori aishi tsuranuku
To protect, to love, to stand my ground
keshite ubawasenai
I won't allow myself to lose anything again
kedakai hana no you ni
Like a noble flower
hitamuki na jounetsu de
With single-minded passion
zankoku na sadame sae
Even if faced with a cruel fate
kirihiraite miseru kara
I will push through
Episode 18:
Ties of Destiny
あっち行ってみよう
Let's try that way.
Okay.
シンアをまた一人でお留守番させちゃったから
早く緑龍探さないとね
We made Sin-ha stay behind alone again.
We'd better find the Green Dragon soon.
異様にいたたまれないもんね
He's been strangely restless.
キジャ 緑龍は
Ki-ja, where's the Green Dragon?
この町にいると思いますが
I believe he's in this town,
とても素早い奴で ちょこまかと動くんですよ
but he's very quick and keeps darting around.
You're in the way! Move!
ほら 退けや
止めてください
Stop!
Please stop!
うるせぇ
Shut up!
Wh-What's going on?
な なに
役人が店で暴れてるみたいだな
Looks like an official's going
on a rampage in that store.
いけません 姫様
You mustn't, Princess.
でも
But...
ここは私が
Allow me to handle this.
てめぇは目立つだろう
You'll draw too much attention.
引っ込んでろ 俺が
Stay out of this. I'll...
That goes for you too, Thunder Beast.
あんたもな 雷獣
この珍獣共 立場分かってんの
Do you wild beasts understand
the position you're in?
しかし
But...
町の人が噂してたけど
The townsfolk are saying...
夕べクムジの船が海賊に沈められたってことで
that the officials are on edge because some pirates sank one of Kum-ji's ships last night.
役人達 気が立ってるんだよ
I know how you feel,
but we need to lie low.
気持ちは分かるけど 今は大人しくして
What were those idiots thinking?
ほら 彼奴らも行ったよ
Look. They've already left.
Yeah.
行こう
Let's go.
Hey.
俺はちょっと別行動する
I'm going off on my own.
姫さんを頼む
Look after the princess.
Huh? Wait, Thunder Beast!
ちょっと 雷獣
What's gotten into him?
いきなりなんだ
Pfft
Pfffft
How ugly!
美しくない
But I get it! I understand what it's trying to say!
しかし分かる 言いたいことは分かる
まぁこれで彼がお尋ねものになったんなら 誘いやすい
If this means he's a wanted man now,
he'll be easier to recruit.
誰を誘いやすいって
Who'll be easier to recruit?
Well, the thing is that I have
no idea what his name is.
あ それが名前全然知らないんだよね
Wait, whoa!
Should you be laughing?
てめぇは笑ってる場合かよ
あんたの顔も 人相書きに出てんじゃねぇか
Your picture and description are up there too.
僕
Mine?
What a delightful face.
これも愉快な顔だね
あんたの顔だ
It's your face.
よく聞こえなかったな
I didn't hear you.
It's your face.
あんたの顔だ
Destroyed
奴ら 目腐ってやがるね
They must be blind.
Destroyed
I agree.
まったくだ
Destroyed
あそう 君
Oh, right! You...
目的を忘れるとこだった
I nearly forgot why I came.
僕は君に会いに来たんだよ
I came here to see you.
Huh? I'm not going back to that place.
あ 俺 もうあぁいう店に行かねぇぞ
違う違う 今日は僕はね
No, no. Today, I...
君が欲しい
I want you.
Murmur
Whisper
おれ そういう趣味ないんで
I'm not into that.
Ah, w-wait, wait.
あぁ ちょっ ちょっと
違うんだ 違うんだよ
I didn't mean it like that!
僕は君のことをいい男だと思って
I just think you're a handsome man.
ここじゃなんだから 人のないところで話を
Why don't we talk somewhere more private?
What are you planning to do to me
if there's no one around?!
人気のねぇところに行って
どうするつもりだ てめぇ
I...
僕は...
You're annoying!
うぜぇ
しまった 少し強く殴り過ぎたか
Crap. Did I hit him too hard?
H-He smiled.
笑いやがった
鼻血出てんのに なんて嬉しそうな目してやがる
Why does he look so happy
when his nose is bleeding?
Per
vert
変態だ
Per
vert
He's a pervert!
Per
vert
今の拳
That punch was a real turn-on.
感じたよ
Crap. He's saying something.
やべぇ なにか言ってる
こいつは危険だ
This guy's bad news!
僕から逃げられると
You think you can run from me?
Hak...
ハク
Princess, what are you doing here?
姫さん なぜここに
このあたり 緑龍の気配がしたんだって
He sensed the Green Dragon in this area.
What?
なに
私はあちらを探してみる
I'm going to search over there!
Hey, wait.
ハクはなにしてたの
Hak, what were you doing?
I was being chased by a pervert.
変態に追いかけられてた
変態
A pervert?
You don't need to know the details, Princess.
いいんだ 姫さんは知らなくて
彼奴 もう追ってきてねぇな
He stopped following me.
初めて人間が怖いと思った
That's the first time I've felt afraid of a human.
二度と関わるまい
I should steer clear of him.
行こう 姫さん
Let's go, Princess.
Yeah.
The White Dragon came close again.
白龍がまた近くまで来たよ
今はそれどころじゃないのに
I don't have time for him right now.
これじゃ彼を海賊に勧誘できないじゃないか
At this rate, I won't be able to convince that guy to join the pirates.
でも僕は狙ったものは逃がさない
But I never let my prey escape.
悪いけど しつこいんだ
Sorry, but I'm persistent.
口説き直しだ
I need to try convincing him again.
この気配は
This presence...
Ouch.
我ながら丈夫な体...
I'm quite tough, if I say so myself-
この人があの女性を助けた人
This is the man who saved
that woman from the officials?
そうっすね まったく関わり合いない人間だけど
Yeah, but I want nothing to do with him.
会ってみたいわ
I'd like to meet him.
止めた方がいいですよ
You shouldn't.
さっきの店だ
That's the store we passed earlier.
Princess!
姫さん
Yona!
ヨナ
Excuse me...
あの
He won't move.
動かないんです
子供が役人に歯向かって 殴られて
Our son was struck when
he stood up to the officials.
And since then...
それきり
動かないんです
he hasn't moved.
If we'd gone to help them...
あの時 助けに入っていれば
Hak...
ハク
どうすれば
How... How can we help these people?
どうすればあの人達を助けてあげられる
ヨナ 今の俺らには何の力もない
Yona, we're powerless right now.
分かってる ユン
I know, Yun.
でも 私は無力であることに甘えてはいけない
However, I can't keep using
my powerlessness as an excuse.
この町が
If this town has been ruined since my father's time, I must do something.
父上の時代から歪んでいるのなら 尚更
どうして どうしてこんなことができるの
How? How can they do something like this?
Is there really nothing I can do?
私は本当になにもできないの
僕は 初めて自分がアホだと思ったよ
That's the first time I've thought
of myself as an idiot.
子供のころ 緑龍の里という檻から漸く抜け出し
When I was a child, I escaped from
the prison of the Green Dragon village.
幾度か らしくないのに 身を潜め
Several times, uncharacteristically,
他の龍に見つからないよう気配を押し殺し
I even concealed my presence so the other dragons wouldn't find me.
漸く見つけた安寧の地
Then I finally discovered this peaceful place.
これからも逃げ延びる自信があったんだけどね
I was sure I could keep running if I had to.
そのうちが 穴に壺が見事にフィットして動けないなんてね
And in the end, this pot fit my butt so perfectly that I can't move!
I don't care about anything anymore!
もうどうでもいいよ全てが
さて 何だっけ 初めまして 白龍君
Now, where were we?
Nice to meet you, White Dragon.
ずっと会いたくなかったけど
さすが僕と同じ龍の血を持つ者
I never wanted to meet you, but clearly, you also possess a dragon's blood.
白い龍が かくも美しい青年だとは
The White Dragon is a beautiful young man, as well.
緑龍見つけました
I found the Green Dragon!
え このまま行くの
Huh? We're going like this?
We're bound by fate.
なんという縁 緑龍が空から降ってくるとは
I can't believe the Green Dragon fell from the sky.
W-Wait, White Dragon...
ちょちょちょ 白龍君
We'll draw too much attention like this.
このままでは目立ってしまう 我々は目立っちゃまずいだろう
We don't want that, do we?
おや そなた妙な尻をしておるな
Oh? You have quite a strange bottom.
どんだけ膨らんでんだい 僕の尻は
Just how fat do you think my butt is?
ずっとそなたを探していた
I've been looking for you.
え このまま会話するの
What? We're going to talk like this?
我々の主がお待ちだ
Our master is waiting for us.
四龍の兄弟よ ともにあのお方をお守りするのだ
My dragon brother, we must
protect our master together.
守るって なんだい
Protect? Why?
そいつ王かなにか
Is this person a king or something?
いや 今はそうではないが あのお方は...
No, not at the moment, but she is-
Unfortunately...
生憎
僕は今の生活が気に入っているし やりたいこともある
I like my current life,
and there are things I want to do.
というわけで 知らない他人が来いといっても行く気はないんだ
So I won't be following some stranger who just asks me to come with him.
Sorry about that.
ごめんなさいね
Wait. Aren't you a dragon?
待って そなたは龍だろう
龍は主を守るため生きて死ぬ者だ
The dragons live and die in order to protect the king.
数千年の時を経て漸く
漸く主が我々を迎えに来られたのだぞ
After thousands of years,
our master has finally come for us.
我々は血を繋ぐだけの龍ではない
We have inherited not only
the blood of the dragons
歴代の龍が成したくとも成しえなかった悲願を
but also the great wish past generations could not fulfill, even if they wanted to.
Good grief.
よりによって人形のような龍が迎えに来たものだ
The dragon who came to find me turned out to be a mere puppet.
歴代の龍達の悲願の中に 君の思考はあるのかい
Does this great wish of the past dragons include your own thoughts too?
何の疑問もなく
If you mean obeying orders without question to protect my master,
ただ言われるがまま 主を守るとか言っているのなら
それは悲願じゃなくて悲劇だね
that would be not my greatest wish
but my greatest tragedy.
可哀想な白龍
Poor White Dragon.
居た
There he is.
Hey.
Ugh.
Hey, now. Sorry about earlier.
ややや さっきはごめんよ
君と話したくてさ
I only wanted to talk.
My grandfather told me
not to speak to strangers.
知らない人と口を利くなというのが爺ちゃんの遺言で
ジェハ 僕の名前だよ
Jae-ha.
That's my name. I'm also a pirate.
ついでに言うと 海賊だ これでもう 知らない奴じゃないだろう
Now we aren't strangers, right?
俺になんの用だ
What do you want with me?
My captain wants you.
僕んとこの船長がね 君をご所望なんだ
君の力に惚れたよ ぜひその力 僕らとともに...
She's enamored by your strength,
and she'd like you to use that strength to-
断る
Not interested.
一回でいい うちの船長に会って欲しいんだ
Just meet my captain once.
君のご主人様も一緒でいいからさ
Your master can come along too.
もっと断る
Even less interested.
よっぽと大事なご主人様らしいね
Your master must be quite important to you.
心配しなくても...
You don't have to worry.
Hak, thanks for waiting.
ハク お待たせ
あら 何方
Who are you?
これよりお前たちは我々の分身
You are now our other halves.
緋龍を主とし 命の限り これを守り
これを愛し 決して裏切るな
You will serve Hiryuu as your master, protecting him with your lives.
You will love him and never betray him.
M-My leg is throbbing.
あ 足が疼く
血が 沸騰するようだ
I feel as though my blood is boiling.
どうした おい
What's wrong? Hey.
大丈夫
Are you okay?
まさか
Is this girl...
この子がずっと遠ざけてきた 四龍を統べる者
the ruler of the four dragons that I've been avoiding?
You're burning up.
凄い熱
行けない
No.
早く ここを立ち去らなければ
I have to leave immediately.
でも なぜ動けない
But why can't I move?
なぜだ こんなにも離れがたいと思うのは
Why is it so difficult for me to pull away?
Thank you, miss. I'm fine now.
ありがとうお嬢さん もう大丈夫
The Green Dragon?
緑龍
貴方緑龍でしょう
You're the Green Dragon, aren't you?
なんで
How...
It's just a feeling.
なんとなくそんな気がするの
違う
Am I wrong?
なんのことだか
I don't know what you're talking about.
僕はただの通りすがりの...
I'm just a passerby-
Princess, that's the Green Dragon!
姫様 その者が緑龍です
通りすがりの
A passerby?
Squeeze
緑龍です
I'm the Green Dragon.
Squeeze
あんたが緑龍だったのか
So you're the Green Dragon.
もう二度と関わりたくなかったｎに
And I wanted nothing more to do with you.
あら あなた人相書きの
Oh, are you the wanted man?
ハクから話を聞いて 会ってみたかったの
After Hak told me about you,
I wanted to meet you.
あなたが緑龍で嬉しい
I'm glad you're the Green Dragon.
It seems I underestimated the connection between the four dragons and Hiryuu.
どうやら四龍と緋龍の結びつきを舐めていたようだ
私はヨナ あなたの名は
I'm Yona. What's your name?
その姿 その声すらも まるで甘い誘惑だ
Her image and voice are like a sweet seduction.
だが これは僕の中の龍の血がそうさせてるだけ
But it's only the dragon's blood inside that makes me feel this way.
僕自身の思いではない
These are not my own feelings!
初めまして 僕の名はジェハ
Nice to meet you. My name is Jae-ha.
僕は心底 会いたくなかったよ お嬢さん
I really didn't want to meet you, miss.
私が来ることを知っていたの
You knew I would come?
I wasn't expecting such a cute girl,
こんな可愛らしい女の子だとは思わなかったけど
ここ最近 白龍と青龍の気配がしてたからね
but I sensed the presence of the White and Blue Dragons lately.
もし彼らが主人を引き連れてやってきたら
言おうと思ってたんだ
If they brought their master with them, I'd planned to tell them this.
僕は君に仕える気はない お帰りください とね
"I have no intention of serving you. Please leave."
私は白龍と青龍の主ではないわ
I'm not the master of the White or Blue Dragons.
今は訳あって 力を貸してもらっているの
I've asked them to lend me their strength.
貴方にも力を貸して欲しくて来たの
I came because I'd like yours, as well.
可愛い女の子に頼られるのは嬉しいな だけどごめんな
I enjoy having cute girls depend on me, but I'm sorry.
僕は白龍のように緋龍王のために生きて死ぬ
なんて志は持ち合わせていないんだ
Unlike the White Dragon, I don't wish to live and die for King Hiryuu.
僕は守るべき人は自分で選ぶし
I will choose whom I wish to protect, and I will choose where I die, as well.
死ぬ場所も自分で決める
だから お嬢さんに力を貸す気はないよ
I have no intention of helping you, miss.
ジェハ そんなに威嚇しなくて大丈夫よ
Jae-ha...
you don't need to try to intimidate me.
I understand.
分かった
貴方のことは諦める
I'll give up on you.
Princess...
姫様
私はお願いしているのであって
命令しているのではないもの
I'm only asking for a favor,
not issuing a command.
あっさり引き下がるんだね
You're just going to withdraw?
ここまではっきり言われて
聞き分けないのも見苦しいわ
After such a clear rejection, it would be disgraceful to act unreasonably.
本当は すっごく残念よ
Actually, this really saddens me!
なぜかしら 四龍に会うと
とても離れがたい気持ちになるのは
For some reason, once I meet a dragon warrior, it's really difficult for me to leave him.
僕も残念だよ
I'm a bit sad too.
久々に会った可愛い子ちゃんだったのに
It's been a long time since I met such a cute girl.
それに 彼を仲間にするつもりだったのにな
Besides...
I had intended to recruit him.
聞き分けないのは見苦しいぜ
It's disgraceful to act unreasonably.
ハクを
You mean Hak?
こいつ海賊なんだと
Apparently, he's a pirate.
俺に船長に会えって さっきからうるせぇ
He won't shut up about me meeting his captain.
つれないな
You're so cold.
海賊
A pirate?
私 貴方達の船長と話がしてみたい
I want to speak with your captain.
なぜ ハクをくれるの
Why? Are you giving us Hak?
Absolutely Not
うんうん あげない
No, I'm not.
Absolutely Not
あなた達が戦っているのは
阿波の領主 ヤンクムジなのでしょう
You're fighting against
Lord Yan Kum-ji of Awa, aren't you?
それがなにか
So what if we are?
役人に殺される子供を見たの
I saw a child killed by an official.
思い出すと 今でも怒りで震えが止まらない
I still quiver with rage when I think about it.
役人にも ヤンクムジにも
At the official, at Yan Kum-ji...
何もできあなった自分にも
and at my own inability to act.
私は理不尽に殺される子供をもう見たくない
I don't want to see any more
children killed unjustly.
Miss, I don't know if we can join forces,
お嬢さんに協力を頼むかは置いといて
ハクを連れて来るなら 船長に合わせよう
but if you're willing to bring Hak,
I'll take you to my captain.
明日 僕らの船においで
Come to our ship tomorrow.
驚かさないでよ
Don't surprise me like that.
急に海賊に会いたいなんて
I can't believe you suddenly said
you wanted to meet pirates.
ごめんね 相談もなしに
I'm sorry for not discussing it with you first.
どうしても 海賊の船長に会ってみたくて
I just really want to meet their captain.
乱暴されたらどうすんのさ
What are you going to do if they get violent?
これは私の独断だから ユンはお留守番してて
This was my decision.
You stay here, Yun.
バカにしないでよね 俺も行くよ
Don't mock me! I'm going with you!
私もお供します
I will join you as well.
よりによって人形のような龍が迎えに来たものだ
The dragon who came to find me
turned out to be a mere puppet.
ハクは強制参加だけど
Hak, you're forced to come with me.
いいっすよ
It's fine. It annoys me that things seem to be going his way, though.
なんか奴の思い通りになってる気がして癪だけど
奴を仲間にするのは もういいんですかい
Are you sure you want to give up
on having him join us?
ジェハが嫌なら仕方ないわ
If Jae-ha doesn't want to,
I don't have a choice.
物わかりがいいことで
You're so understanding.
You weren't so understanding
俺が風の部族を出る時は
行くのを許した覚えはないだの
when I tried to leave the Wind Tribe
or when you demanded that I be yours.
ハクを頂戴だのわがまま放題
姫さん
Princess?
煩いわね お前は別よ
Shut up. You're different.
別
Different?
別って どう別なんです
Different? Different how?
どうもこうもないわよ 昔のことを掘り返さないで
It's not worth discussing.
Don't dig up the past.
Come to think of it, you did say I was
the only one who had to stay by your side.
そういえば ハクだけは側にいなくちゃダメとか言ってましたよね
I hate that side of you!
お前のそういうところが嫌い
はい はい ご飯できましたよ
Okay, okay. Food's ready.
私はヨナ 貴方が船長さん
I'm Yona. Are you the captain?
船長 ギガンだよ
I'm Captain Gi-gan.
話はジェハから聞いてるよ
Jae-ha told me about you.
私達に協力したいんだってね
He said you want to help us.
Yes.
It's a girl.
女の子だ
可愛いな
She's cute!
っていうか
But wait...
なんだい その面は
What's with the mask?
Exactly, Captain!
だよね 船長
It's awfully curious, isn't it?
気になるのそこだよね
取りな
Take it off!
No, stop.
Leave me alone.
顔を見せな
No, stop.
Leave me alone.
Show me your face!
No, stop.
Leave me alone.
He's incredibly shy!
そいつは極度の恥ずかしがりやなの
No, stop.
Leave me alone.
私は一番大事にしてるのはね 信頼だよ
Above all else, I value trust.
信用できない奴等に協力なんて誰が頼むかい
Who would ask for help from
someone they can't trust?
でも戦力がいるんだろ 船長
But you need fighters, don't you, Captain?
こいつらを全員のしたら 合格だよ
If you can beat all these guys, you pass.
船長 こりゃいくらなんでも 多勢に無勢っしょう
Captain, don't you think
these numbers are unfair?
Yeah, you're right. This is too many, right?
そうだな これはあんまりだ な
Yes.
私/俺 一人でも十分やれる
I can handle this on my own.
Let's see you try!
やってみろぜ
如何ですか
How was that?
I bet you want us now, Captain Gi-gan.
ギガン船長 欲しくなったらろう
Don't, Captain. Their strength is extraordinary.
ダメだよ こいつらの力は規格外だ
僕が三人いるようなもんなんだから
It would be like having three of me.
You pass.
合格
Good.
よかった
Yeah.
安心するのは早いよ 小僧共
Don't relax yet, kids.
お前はなにができるんだい
What can you do?
I don't like violence, so I don't fight.
俺は暴力嫌いだから 戦わないよ
Aside from fighting, I can do anything.
それ以外ならなんでもできる
料理 裁縫 狩猟 怪我人の治療 材料があれば爆薬も作れる
Cooking, sewing, hunting, treating the wounded.
With the right ingredients,
I can even make explosives.
あと 美少年
Also, I'm a handsome young man.
I see.
なるほど
で お前は
What about you?
Uh...
お前はなにができる
What can you do?
私 私ができるのは...
I... I can...
ないんだね
You can't do anything.
ここで何もできない奴は足手まといだよ
Those who can't do anything
will only slow us down.
I...
わ 私
Plenty of people in this town hate Kum-ji.
クムジが憎い奴はこの町に山ほどいるさ
でも力がなければ 刃向っても命を落とすだけ
But if they lack the strength,
they'll only die by standing against him.
There's nothing you can do, girl. Leave.
お前のような小娘には無理だよ 帰んな
この方が一緒でなければ 我々は貴様などは...
Without her, we will not work with-
Ki-ja, it's all right.
キジャ いいの
ギガン船長の言う通りだわ
Captain Gi-gan is right.
But...
だけど
私にも 引けない理由がある
I have my own reasons for not backing down!
いい目をしてるじゃないか
I like the look in her eyes.
いいだろう
Very well. You'll do a job to prove to me...
お前が役に立つかどうか
信頼にたる人間かどうか
一つ仕事をやってもらおうじゃないか
that you're useful and worthy of my trust.
命がけの仕事ね
A life-threatening job.
modoranai hibi ni namida koboshite
Crying tears for the days that won't return
miageta sora ga akaku akaku moeru
You look up to the sky, and it's burning bright red
jibun no tsuyosa yowasa kizuketa no nara ima
Now that you know your own strength and weakness
kimi yo osoreruna kokoro omomuku mama
You should have no fear and go where your heart takes you
kaze wo kirisusumu sono tabiji wo
Cleaving through the wind, your path is lit
akatsuki ga terasu
By the dawn
(tsudoe takeki kaina)
(Gather, fierce arm)
(senri no hitomi)
(All-seeing eyes)
sora wo kakeyuku ashi
Feet that dash through the sky
(kuon no tate)
(Shield of eternity)
inishie no chikai ima hatashite
Fulfill the ancient vows
yoru yo akete yuke
O night, break into dawn
Next Time
足よ 動け
Move, legs!
Little by little, one step at a time.
少しつつでも 一方つつでも
If I can beat this fear, surely...
この恐怖に打ち勝てば きっと...
次回 暁のヨナ 第十九話
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 19:
Episode 19:
The Senjuso Test
千樹草の試し
The Senjuso Test.